Finding Aid for Wesleyan Methodist Church, Michigan Conference records, 1852-1942
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Wesleyan Methodist Church, Michigan Conference records [microform] 1842-1952
Wesleyan Methodist Connection (or Church) of America. Michigan Conference.
3 microfilm reels
86289 Ba Microcopy
Minutes, financial material, membership statistics, and biographies of ministers; and minutes, 1857-1916, of the Leoni Wesleyan Church.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The microfilming of the records was made possible through the Rev. Ernest L. Crocker (donor no. 2407 ).
No further additions to the records are expected.
The record group is open to research.
The Wesleyan Methodist Church originated in 1843 after members of the Methodist Episcopal Church withdrew from that church to organize a non-episcopal, antislavery church. The Wesleyan Church is considered one of the Holiness Churches. It stresses entire sanctification, a postconversion experience that allows the person to live a sinless life.
The records include microfilm copies of conference minutes, 1852-1942 and a volume containing Leoni Wesleyan minutes, 1857- ca. 1860, and records of the Mutual Improvement Association of Michigan Conference, 1871-1917. The originals of these records are in the Archives, Wesleyan Church, Marion, Ind.
Subjects:
Leoni (Mich.); Leoni Wesleyan Church (Leoni, Mich.); Wesleyan Methodist Connection (or Church) of America--Michigan--Leoni.; Wesleyan Methodist Connection (or Church) of America. Michigan Conference.
- Conference minutes
  - 1852-1867 (Reel 1)
  - 1868-1884 (Reel 1)
  - 1885-1907 (Reel 1)
  - 1908-1918 (Reel 2)
  - 1919-1926 (Reel 2)
  - 1927-1934 (Reel 2)
  - 1935-1942 (Reel 3)
- Combined record book
  - Leoni Wesleyan minutes, 1857-ca. 1860 (Reel 3)
  - Mutual Improvement Association of Michigan Conference, 1871-1917 (Reel 3)